<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Neelu S. Kalani</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Neelu S. Kalani</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/research/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;research-interests&#34;&gt;Research Interests&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- &lt;figure class=&#34;avatar2&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/neelu-photo-paris.jpeg&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;avatar&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA; --&gt;&#xA;&lt;div align=&#34;justified&#34;&gt;&#xA;My research interests broadly include confidential computing, computer systems and computer architecture. Recently, during my PhD, my interests revolve around building trustworthy systems (confidential computing environments, isolation monitors, root of trust, trusted runtimes) and RISC-V. During my masters, I worked on the microarchitectural side of things such as optimising the performance of micro-op caches (at Intel Labs) and optimising energy and performance of hardware cache prefetchers.   &#xA;&lt;hr style=&#34;height:2px;border-width:0;color:gray;background-color:gray&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- &lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;PhD Thesis&lt;/u&gt;:&lt;/b&gt; My PhD thesis has so far revolved around building trustworthy systems. --&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;building-trustworthy-systems&#34;&gt;Building Trustworthy Systems&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Traditionally, cloud service providers (CSP) have been bestowed with immense control over their customer&amp;rsquo;s data. The purpose of confidential cloud computing is to take this control from the CSP and grant it to customers instead. Though the design space in this field has been widely explored in the last decade, there are obstacles in the form of prioprietary and specialised designs which can keep confidential cloud computing from reach its potential. With my advisor (Prof. Edouard Bugnion), colleagues at EPFL and collaborators at Microsoft Research Cambridge, we are trying to rethink the solution by keeping the entire systems stack in perspective. To this end, we are building a versatile isolation monitor which provides a new system abstraction of trust domains. Trust domains are isolated orthogonally to existing system abstractions and privilege hierarchies. The isolation monitor, called Tyche (the Greek goddess of fate, some say Tyche lets &amp;ldquo;good things happen&amp;rdquo;), leverages existing hardware security primitives to isolate trust domains. For instance, Intel VT-x on x86 and PMPs on RISC-V. I am personally responsible for the development of Tyche on RISC-V for QEMU and StarFive VisionFive2. If you find this interesting, check out our &lt;a href=&#34;https://dl.acm.org/doi/abs/10.1145/3593856.3595900&#34;&gt;HotOS 2023 paper&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
